Taiye Ajimati

Front-End Developer

★ taiyeajimati@gmail.com in linkedin C Github ⊕ Portfolio

**Tolion C Github ⊕ Portfolion C Github ⊕ Portfolion

**Tolion C Github ⊕ Portfolion C Github ⊕ Portfolion

**Tolion C Github

ABOUT ME

An experienced front-end developer with over 2 years of practical experience in web development and product design. Over the years, I have worked as a Graphic and product designer creating visually appealing products for small and large firms.

I am passionate about building accessible and responsive web applications using React is, JavaScript, CSS, TailwindCSS, Sass, and SQL while managing my code base using version control platforms like GitHub.

RELEVANT SKILLS

Programming Languages

Javascript (ES6), HTML, CSS/Sass, TailwindCSS, Python

Libraries & Frameworks

React, Node is, TailwindCSS, Next is

Tools & Platforms

Github, Wordpress, Vercel

Design

Figma, Adobe xd, Photoshop, Illustrator, Indesign

EDUCATION

B.Eng Computer Engineering

Federal University of Technology, Minna Niger-State.

2012-2017

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Freelance Front-End Developer

Presently

Presently working as a freelance front-end developer and constantly looking out for opportunities and projects that requires my skills and expertise in developed an accessible and scalable software products.

Web/UI Designer (PT/Contract)

@ Sprout Digital Development

Nov. 2019 - Till date

Web Developer/ICT Assistant

@ Sprout Digital Development

March 2018 - Sept. 2019

Job Description:

- Created website layout and user interface using standard HTML, CSS & Javascript practices.
- Managed the company's web hosting platform.
- Maintained, expanded, and scaled different clients' websites.
- Created User Interfaces for specialized websites.
- Created graphic designs for web, social media ads & banners, print, and marketing collaterals as required.

Graphic Designer

@ 240 Media

August. 2012 - Feb.2018

Job Description:

- Created custom brand documents for the various clients.
- Created website and social media ads banners, Graphic design using Adobe suite and Coreldraw.
- Incorporate changes recommended by clients or art directors into final designs.
- Review designs for errors before printing or publishing them.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

codeIT Summer Holiday @ August 2018 - October 2019

Instructional Facilitator - Trained kids under age 16 the basics of programming

YouthhubAfrica @ October 2019 - December 2019

Creative Designer - Volunteered as part of a multimedia team that managed the publicity of a yearly conference organized by YouthhubAfrica.